Andrii Aheiev

DevOps, Cloud Architect

Amstelveen, The Netherlands

mail: a.ageyev@gmail.com skype: a.ageyev

LinkedIn | GitHub | Bitbucket | Puppet Forge



Design, build, automate infrastructure and CI/CD processes

DevOps Engineer with 12+ years of experience in managing cloud infrastructure, ci/cd processes and automation. Practical experience in Kubernetes administration, Linux and database management.

- Designing and implementing infrastructure as code for AWS, Azure, Google Cloud, DigitalOcean, etc.
- Designing, implementing, securing and automating CI/CD processes and application infrastructure using micro-services architecture.
- Design and support application migration from VM-based infrastructure to dockerized micro-services in Kubernetes.
- Bringing operation requirements to software engineering and provide maximum scalability and availability for applications and services.

Building and optimizing cloud applications infrastructure

Describe OS, software, network, computer resources configuration and create Infrastructure and Configuration As Code with Terraform, Ansible, Puppet, and other tools on different clouds: AWS, Azure, Google Cloud, DigitalOcean, etc.

- Optimizing infrastructure and application for high load.
- Implement infrastructure as code and change management.
- Design and implement application, infrastructure and security monitoring.
- Implement notification policies and define escalation rules.
- Create backup and disaster recovery process. Implement data archiving.

Implementing CI/CD processes for dockerized apps and Kubernetes

Automate CI/CD processes with Jenkins, Azure DevOps, Teamcity (or other) pipelines to implement

- Build application with docker. Move build configuration to the Dockerfile.
- Publish and promote docker image to container registry
- Deploy docker container to Kubernetes with helm and run integrational tests
- Run integration, acceptance or distributed performance testing
- Deploy application to development environment and trigger release pipelines

Machine Learning workflows automation and CI/CD

- Dynamic environment for ML train processes in Kubernetes or Computer Cloud
- Microservice configuration and profiling for ML prediction application
- Build, test and deploy pipelines for Kubernetes

Experience

Feb 2020 – now

Site Reliability Engineer

XLinQ / ING. Contract

Azure AKS Docker Kubernetes Helm Automation CI/CD Azure DevOps Azure Pipelines Aqua Security CISO SEM IaC PostgreSQL Azure Service Bus Kafka

Infrastructure development and CI/CD processes automation

- Infrastructure cloud design and configuration in Azure
- Micro-services design and full lifecycle implementation (build, test, Kubernetes deploy)
- CI/CD processes automation with Azure DevOps
- Infrastructure/application monitoring design and implementation with Azure Monitoring and Log Analytics
- Security monitoring. Implementation of CISO and SEM rules with Azure Sentinel
- Kubernetes infrastructure and ci security for docker images

June 2018 - Jan 2020

Docker Kubernetes helm Automation Jenkins CI/CD Ansible Azure AWS Groovy Ruby Airflow ML H2O Kafka Kinesis Jetty Ruby .Net MSSQL

Senior DevOps

PitneyBowes. Contract

Development infrastructure and CI/CD processes automation

- Jenkins CI/CD Pipelines: build, test, publish and deploy micro-services (NodeJS, Dotnet with Docker and Kubernetes). Release preparation.
- Application infrastructure design and implementation with docker and Kubernetes (AKS, EKS)
- Design and implementation Machine Learning CI/CD pipelines (train, test and deploy prediction application)

What was done:

- Dockerized complex .Net event-processing application and created set of microservices
 - a. Application requirements (health checks, logging, resources profiling, etc.)
 - b. Local Dev / Test environment with docker-compose
 - c. QA/ Stage / prod environment deploys in Kubernetes using helm charts
 - d. Integration testing
- 2. Events synchronization from Kafka to AWS Kinesis
 - a. Local model with docker-compose
 - b. Permanent Azure AWS events synchronization implemented on AKS
- 3. Infrastructure migration from Azure to AWS (development and CI/CD)
- 4. ML prediction app pipelines design and automation
 - a. Dynamic H2O cluster
 - b. Docker jetty container with H2O models
 - c. Deploy and performance testing

May 2017 - May 2018

Senior WebOps

AWS Ansible Jenkins Ruby Automation Backup Archiving

Provectus for Determine. Contract

SaaS Product infrastructure and processes automation.

Infrastructure and processes automation (AWS, Jenkins)

Backup and archiving processes automation for files and Oracle Databases (RDS)

What was implemented:

- Redesigned and implemented automated process for SaaS backup and archiving
- Created custom inventory service with scheduled information update
- Improved monitoring processes

Oct 2016 - Apr 2017

DevOps Architect

Nest. Contract

Google Cloud Automation Ansible Puppet Terraform Jira Confluence MySQL Atlassian AWS Puppet MPI Cluster Docker Bamboo MacOS

Dev Infrastructure migration from AWS to Google Cloud.

- Infrastructure design for Development services in Google Cloud Platform (Atlassian stack and build infrastructure) Automate infrastructure provisioning and configuration.
- Created migration plan to move infrastructure services from AWS cloud to GCP cloud.

May 2012 - Apr 2017

DevOps Architect

Freelancer

Private Cloud, Web Infrastructure VMware MySQL automation CI/CD High-Load Puppet

Full infrastructure and DevOps support for multiple small web-projects

- Cloud infrastructure design and automation
- Domain and SSL management
- Private Cloud design and implementation (VMware, HP, Dell, EMC)
- Infrastructure configuration with Puppet
- Security audit. PCI DCC.

Aug 2005 - Apr. 2012

Lohika

Site IT manager / Ops Lead

Oracle Linux Puppet PHP Ruby VMware Private Cloud RHEL Windows Server Active Directory SLES HP SAN

Entire site operation, IT infrastructure and team management, site IT budget planning. Communication with software and hardware vendors and resellers. Communication with local service-providers.

On that position:

- Prepared budget for Private Cloud (for local datacenter). Dealing directly with software and hardware resellers to get best term and prices.
- Design and deployment of Private Cloud on external datacenter.
- Implemented new workflow to delivery resources to DEV and QA, which allows us to more flexible planning and managing resources.
- Designed and implemented IT infrastructure for two new office-spaces in Odessa. (Telephony, networking, conference-rooms, etc.)

Senior IT / DevOps

Installing and managing different application environments with separated or shared DB (Oracle, MySQL, SQL) Linux Administrator, Oracle DBA – support all instances of Oracle RDBMS on entire the site

On that position:

- Build from scratch Virtual Private Cloud on existing hardware. Implement new workflow to ordering new resources to existing Cloud
- Provide internal education on Red Hat Linux, Oracle DB to QA and developers

Apr 2003 - Aug 2005

Software Engineer / DBA

TWT Ukraine

Linux FreeBSD MySQL Telecom Perl PHP DialUp PostgreSQL

Development and support for telecom billing.

On that position:

- Changed core database from MySQL to PostgreSQL
- Business logic moved from different system parts written on C++, Perl and PHP to PostgreSQL stored procedures
- Optimizer and automated reporting processes

Education

<u>1998 - 2003</u> **Odesa State Polytechnic University**

Computer and Network Systems

2016 MongoDB University

M102. MongoDB for DBA

<u>2011</u> **HP Education center**

VMware vSphere 4.0 – Deploy, Configure, Manage

<u>2006</u> Kvazar Micro Education center

Oracle 10G Administrator